{"tossups": [{"question": "This dynasty\u2019s capital was moved when the king attempted to avoid joining the \u201cstrife of the Princes.\u201dThe Hall of Worthies was established by this dynasty to promote research. Toyotomi Hideyoshi\u2019s attempts to conquer this dynasty were thwarted after the Battle of Myeongnyang, where Yi Sun-sin used turtle ships to defeat the Japanese navy. This dynasty became known as the \u201cHermit Kingdom\u201d for its isolationism. For the point, name this Korean dynasty that was ruled by Sejong the Great.", "answer": "<b> Joseon</b> Dynasty", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This thinker originated the adage \u201cif the only thing you have is a hammer\u201d \u201cit is tempting [...] to treat everything as a nail.\u201d This thinker coined a term for people who fear success, the \u201cJonah Complex,\u201d and wrote<em> The Farther Reaches of Human Nature</em> in which he discussed \u201cpeak experiences.\u201d In a landmark 1943 work, this thinker developed a scale that begins with physiological motivations and culminates with self-actualization. For the point, name this psychologist who developed a \u201chierarchy of needs.\u201d", "answer": "Abraham<b> Maslow</b> Page 1", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {"question": "One ruler of this region gained his nickname for his bravery during the Battle of Nicopolis. Another ruler of this place founded the Order of the Golden Fleece and was the patron of Jan van Eyck. Leaders of this region fought the Armagnacs after previously murdering the Duke of Orleans. The last ruler of this region was defeated by Lorrainian and Swiss armies at the Battle of Nancy, after which this region was annexed by the House of Valois. John the Fearless and Charles the Bold ruled, for the point, what eastern French duchy renowned for its red wine?", "answer": "Duchy of<b> Burgundy</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This writing team listed \u201cWhitney and his cotton gin,\u201d \u201cFulton and his steamboat,\u201d and \u201cFord and his Lizzie\u201d as people who were laughed at in a love song written for Ginger Rogers. DuBose Heyward worked with this team on a work that notes \u201cLi\u2019l David was small, but oh my! He fought big Goliath, who lay down an\u2019 dieth\u201d after warning \u201cThe things that you\u2019re li\u2019ble / to read in the Bible [...] It ain\u2019t necessarily so.\u201d For the point, name this writer/composer team behind<em> Porgy and Bess</em>, a pair of brothers named Ira and George.", "answer": "Ira and George<b> Gershwin</b> (accept the<b> Gerswhin</b> brothers)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "This meeting controversially awarded the town of Olivenca to Portugal, stirring Spanish opposition. The terms of this meeting had been laid out in the Treaty of Chaumont and created the modern Kingdom of the Netherlands. The Final Act summed up the provisions of this meeting, which included the restoration of monarchs to pre-war thrones and the creation of the Concert of Europe. For the point, name this meeting that was staffed by Klemens von Metternich in 1814-15, following the Napoleonic Wars.", "answer": "<b> Congress</b> of<b> Vienna</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Bobby Rush, who instead sought a censure resolution, was the lone representative to vote against rebuking this Congressman for asking \u201cWhite supremacist [...] - how did that language become offensive?\u201d In January 2019, all committee assignments were stripped from, for the point, what Iowa representative with a lengthy history of racist advocacy?", "answer": "Steve<b> King</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The death of policeman David Hennessy in this state led to the lynching of 5 Italians in Tallulah. P.B.S. Pinchback\u2019s victory in an election in this state made him the first African-American governor in U.S. history. A chamber pot was emptied onto David Farragut\u2019s head during a military occupation of this state, whose Civil War-era capital was Shreveport. Benjamin Butler oversaw a military occupation in, for the point, what state where the cotton trade was hampered by Union troops stationed in New Orleans?", "answer": "<b> Louisiana</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In 1968, many viewers missed this team\u2019s two touchdown comeback against the Jets because NBC left the game to broadcast the film<em> Heidi</em>. This team\u2019s longtime owner, Al Davis, refused to play in cities with segregated hotels and repeatedly sued the NFL over his attempts to move the team to, and later from, Los Angeles. This team traded away Amari Cooper and Khalil Mack in 2018 in the first year of Jon Gruden\u2019s second stint as head coach. For the point, name this NFL team that was sued in 2018 over its plans to move to Las Vegas from the San Francisco Bay area.", "answer": "the<b> Raiders</b> (accept<b> Oakland</b> Raiders,<b> L</b>os<b> A</b>ngeles Raiders, and/or<b> Las Vegas</b> Raiders)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "George of Podebrady imprisoned a king of this nation who captured Vienna in 1485 from Frederick III with his Black Army. A king of this country defended Belgrade from the Ottoman Empire in 1456. Suleiman the Magnificent captured this country at the Battle of Mohacs [moh-hotch]. Matthias Corvinus and Janos Hunyadi [YAH-nohsh hoon-yah-dee] were kings of this country, which was ruled for three centuries by the Arpad Dynasty. Saint Stephen I ruled the Magyars in, for the point, what country with capital at Budapest?", "answer": "<b> Hungary</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In 2014, David Robarge publicly released information withheld from this group by John McCone in a \u201cbenign cover-up.\u201d The youngest member of this group defended its report on<em> Face of the Nation</em> and was named Hale Boggs. Arlen Specter helped introduce the \u201csingle bullet theory\u201d to this group, which investigated an event that occurred in Dealey Plaza and was perpetrated by Lee Harvey Oswald. Lyndon Johnson established, for the point, what commission to investigate the assassination of John F. Kennedy led by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court?", "answer": "<b> Warren</b> Commission Page 3", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s early investing in Story Farm made him enough money to purchase the Keystone Bridge Company; he later expanded again by buying out the Homestead factory. This man noted that the wealthy had a duty to improve the lot of the less fortunate in his<em> Gospel of Wealth</em>. In 1901, this man sold his Pittsburgh-based company for 480 million to J.P. Morgan, who rebranded it as US Steel. For the point, name this Scottish-American magnate of the Gilded Age.", "answer": "Andrew<b> Carnegie</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In this city, a shootout with robbers occurred on Gresson Street. While communicating by Charles Elliott by mail, Lord Palmerston called this city a \u201cbarren island with hardly a house.\u201d Murray MacLehose was the longest-serving governor of this colony. Chris Patten served as the final governor of this city before it became governed under Deng Xiaopeng\u2019s \u201cOne Country, Two Systems\u201d principle along with Macau. The Treaty of Nanking transferred, for the point, what island that was reverted back to Chinese control in 1997?", "answer": "British<b> Hong Kong</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "After this region\u2019s elk population decreased, Stewart Udall issued the Leopold Report on ecosystem management. The Washburn Expedition named a famous feature in this region, which was created by an Act of Dedication by Ulysses Grant. The Teton Range range is to the south of this national park, which contains a feature that erupts roughly every 75 minutes. Old Faithful can be found in, for the point, what large national park that was created in 1872 and takes up much of Wyoming?", "answer": "<b> Yellowstone</b> National Park", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "During this war, nuclear weapons were to be employed as part of Operation Duck Hook. An enormous network of tunnels was built during this war at Cu Chi. The Battle of the Ia Drang Valley was a major victory for the eventual losing side of this war, which was led by William Westmoreland. Dozens of cities were attacked simultaneously in the Tet Offensive during, for the point, what war that was launched by the Gulf of Tonkin Resolution and ended with the fall of Saigon?", "answer": "<b> Vietnam</b> War (accept<b> Second Indochina</b> War)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man was dismissed from the militia after a poor showing from his artillery detachment in the Penobscot Expedition. During an escape, this man was forced to abandon William Dawes, who fell off his horse. A Henry Wadsworth Longfellow poem immortalized this man\u2019s most famous action, which was prompted by two lit lanterns in the Old North Church. For the point, name this silversmith known for his\u201cmidnight ride\u201d to warn that \u201cthe British are coming.\u201d", "answer": "Paul<b> Revere</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This leader\u2019s government was compromised when General Pacepa fled to the United States, forcing him to reorganize the Securitate. Pastor Laszlo Tokes [toh-kesh] was pressured to leave his church by this leader, who issued Decree 770 banning abortion. After failing to suppress protests in Timisoara, this dictator was forced to flee, but he and his wife Elena were executed on Christmas Day 1989. For the point, name this last Communist leader of Romania.", "answer": "Nicolae<b> Ceausescu</b> [cho-chess-koo]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This empire\u2019s founder once gave 500 war elephants to Seleucus Nicator, leading to a decisive victory for Seleucus at Ipsus. This empire\u2019s second ruler was born after his mother was poisoned and was named after the drops of blood that appeared on his forehead. The most famous ruler of this empire constructed the Lion Capital pillar at Sarnath and adorned it with declarations of his Buddhist faith. For the point, name this empire once ruled by Bindusara and Ashoka.", "answer": "<b> Maurya</b>n Empire", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "The Praetorian Guard worked for the holder of, for the point, what position first held by Octavian?", "answer": "<b> Roman Emperor</b> (prompt on \u201cEmperor\u201d or \u201cleader of Rome;\u201d do not accept \u201cking of Rome\u201d) <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if moderator botches a question.", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This empire\u2019s capital city was built on top of the older capital of Yasodharapura. This empire was supplied with water by massive reservoirs called barays, and it declined in importance after an invasion by the Cham people. This empire\u2019s capital was located near modern Siem Reap and contains the world\u2019s largest religious complex, Angkor Wat. For the point, name this empire that, for six centuries ending in 1431, ruled what is now Cambodia.", "answer": "<b> Khmer</b> Empire Page 6", "metadata": "History - World History"}], "bonuses": []}